== 时间轴校正：波士顿 ==
主演：尼古拉斯.凯奇
片名：极速60秒
主演：劳勃杜瓦
(星期日，11点58分) 威顿与威瑟街口
Corner of Wiltern and Wetherly.
小飞弄错了 他说保时捷在威顿与威瑟街口
Tumbler messed up. He said the Porsche should be...
at the corner of Wiltern and Wetherly.
它就在这里
- It's right there. - You're bullshittin' me, right?
不会吧…威顿街9O24号?
- 9024 Wiltern? - What? That?
什么，那台?
I gotta get my tool.
我得拿工具
Kip! He ain't bullshittin'.
奇普!他说的是真的
奇普
Kip! That's not a tool. That's a damn brick!
什么鬼工具，那是砖头
要用那玩意儿…乾脆直接跟监狱订房算了
Kip, man, we gonna use a brick, man, we might as well call a prison and make reservations.
别这样
Ah, come on.
去找号码
Get the number.
4285O
42850.
快点
Hurry up, man.
走吧
Man, let's go!
快闪人吧
Let's get the hell outta here.
Okay, Billy Badass, you got us in here.
好了，大神偷
你带我们近来就得带我们出去
Now tell me how the hell we gonna get out.
Oh, no. I know you ain't gonna do what I think you're gonna do.
你不会想那么做吧?
- Oh, man! - Come on!
天啊
快啊
这又不是"不可能的任务"
- This ain't The Dukes of Hazzard. - Come on!
冲啊
听听我的新技巧
Yo, so check out my new move. I call it "The Stranger."
我称之为"坐坐爽
What I do is, I sit on my hand for like 15, 20 minutes...
我坐著我的手，l5到2O分钟直到它变麻
until it goes numb, no feeling at all.
没有知觉，接著...
And then... I rub one out.
再对它狂抽猛送
The Stranger, huh?
坐坐爽?
It's like a little boys' nursery school I've come upon here.
我真觉得自己像幼稚园保姆
他们人呢?
Where are they?
- You want it? All right. - Hey.
别惹他们
- Leave those people alone. - Oh, my God. Sweetie, you're so talented.
甜心，你真够呛的
- Wha... Hey, hey. Stolen car. Stolen car. - I know. I know.
这是贼车、贼车
Hey, I love you.
我爱你
我们会被捕的
Man, we goin' to jail, man!
来啊
Come on!
你有权保持缄点
Keep your hands behind your back. You have the right to remain silent.
小心
Hey, watch it!
有辆银色保时捷，时速约8O哩
We have a silver Porsche. Estimated speed: 80 miles per hour.
在威夏街向西行驶
Heading west on Wilshire Boulevard.
这是制空一号 谦犯在桥上上往南行驶
This is Air One. We have a visual of the suspect southbound...
on Vincent Thomas Bridge.
出状况了?
- Something wrong, Tumbler? - Yeah, I'm missing Jerry Springer.
是啊，我想看"杰瑞开炮"
好耶、好耶...
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
很好、很好
That's right, that's right, that's right, that's right!
你好，大车商
What's up, old man?
她从静止到6O哩只要5.2秒
She'll go zero to 60 in 5.2 seconds.
这点我能证明
Believe me, I can vouch for that.
地面人员
Ground units be advised, suspects last seen entering south side of warehouse.
谦犯已进入货栈南端
Thirteen down, thirty-seven to go.
搞定十三辆，还有三十七辆
那是什么?
- What the hell is that? - What is that, man?
你惹出麻烦了
- Now you've gone and done it, Raines. - Tumbler!
小飞，把字擦掉、拿走灯
- Get the board and get the lights! - I got it, I got it!
This is bullshit. It's not comin' off!
擦不掉
- Keys! Get the keys! - I got 'em. I got 'em!
拿擒匙 我去拿
Come on, everybody! Let's go! Hurry up!
快点
拿到了 走吧
- I got it! - Let's go! Toby, get it!
托比，去拿
- Let's go, boys! - Come on, come on! I got the light!
快走
拿灯
走、快走...
Go, go, go! Let's go!
该死
Shit!
Get the VIN number on that?
- I got it. - We've got a lamp shade by a truck.
What do we got?
查到些什么?
All gone. We didn't get a single one of 'em.
全跑了
一个也没抓到，都是行家
And we are talking about professionals.
车锁、架驶盘、点火装置都完好无伤
No visible damage to locking mechanisms, steering columns or ignitions.
你看，这些可不是三阳喜美
And, as you can see, these are not Honda Civics.
这是新款的宝士
This is one of three brand-new Mercedes,
他们宣称这车能完全防窃
a car they say is unstealable.
除非有从汉堡直接寄来的...
Yeah, unless you get the laser-cut transponder key...
数位雷射车匙
sent directly to the U.S. Dealer from Hamburg.
他们有内应
They got somebody working on the inside.
查出车是哪个车商的 还有其他资料
- Find out which dealership sold them, serviced them, etc., etc. - Yeah, I'll get on it.
我会去查
小戴
- Mr. Drycoff? - Yeah?
扣留这些车一个月
Let's impound these cars for one month. I don't give a damn if they belong to Tom Cruise.
就算车主是汤姆克鲁斯也一样
(星期一，2点l5分)
操控
Control, vision, determination.
抱负
决心
These are the three fundamental components...
这些是新世代赛车手的三项基本要件
of the new generation race car driver.
速度只是副产品，速度很快
Speed is a byproduct. Going fast.
但要记得…车子就是你
But remember: The car is you, you are the car.
你就是车子
好了，上路吧
Okay? Let's ride!
Billy, you just shaved one second off your lap time!
比利，你这圈加快一秒了
汤来，我是要你赛车不是玩碰碰车
Tommy, I don't know what that was, but it wasn't driving.
去追上他们吧
Go get 'em!
Well, well, well. What do you pay your pit crews with?
你拿什么付修车技师?糖果跟饼乾?
Oreos and Gummy Bears?
I folded, Atley. You know that. What are you doing here?
我洗手了，老艾
你有何贵斡?
- Is there someplace we can talk? - About what?
能借一步说话吗? 说什么?
你弟弟，还有他惹上的麻烦
About your brother and the deep shit he's in.
Frank, can you watch the kids for a minute?
法阑?帮我看一下好吗?
奇普怎么了?
Tell me about Kip.
他搞砸工作，现在惨了
He took a job, and he fumbled it.
他真的惨了
Now he's jammed up. He's jammed up bad.
什么工作?
- What kind of job? - A boost. A big boost.
一椿买卖，大买卖
买卖?
A boost?
奇普怎么会做买卖?
What's Kip doing on a boost?
你不是开玩笑吧?
Oh, you're shittin' me, man.
你走之后，奇普就成了头头
Kip's become quite the little crew runner since you left.
You don't talk to your ma?
你没跟你妈联络?
She neglected to mention it.
她忘了提了
Listen, I need something.
始著，我需要喝点冰的
I-I need something cold to drink.
我以为我们会找个地方淡
I thought we were goin' someplace to talk.
帮谁做买卖?
- Who was the job for? - A new guy named Raymond Calitri.
一个叫卡雷蒙的新人
They call him "The Carpenter."
人称"木匠
He's runnin' all the dark ponies down there now.
现在整个长堤都归他管了
他是真正的"魔鬼大帝
It's a full-on "Devil came down to Long Beach" trip.
他很危险
He's bad. He's real bad.
真的很危险
And this Calitri is the one who's after my brother?
这个姓卡的在钉我老弟?
毫不留情
Like stains on a mattress.
你该知道…我在他手下做事
And you should know... I work for him.
跛脚的退休偷车贼
There weren't a lot of opportunities for retired car thieves on the gimp.
就业行情并不好
他让我重回战场
He put me to work.
我得跟你说，曼斐 连我都怕这家伙
I-I gotta tell you, Memphis, this guy, he scares the shit out of even me.
你斡么?
What are you doin', man?
住手
Stop! Stop!
住手…
Atley Jackson.
杰艾利
Got it. They have Kip.
知道了 他们逮住奇普了
带我去
Take me there.
(艾克西特废铁场)
卡雷蒙，雷曼斐
Raymond Calitri, Memphis Raines.
I try...
我试着了解并学习美国人的行为
to learn your ways, understand your obsessions.
但棒球…真是够无聊了
But this baseball... it's so bleeding boring, isn't it?
我弟弟呢?
Where's my brother?
雷曼斐…久仰大名
Memphis Raines, your legend precedes you.
艾利说你是第一好手
Atley tells me you're the best.
你走后
After you left, auto theft in the South Bay area went down 47 percent.
南海区的汽车失窃率就降了百分之四十七
我弟弟呢?
Where's my brother?
我很以这些为傲
I'm proud of these. Straddle chair from the Arts and Crafts period.
工艺时代的椅子
Mahogany table with cloud-lift pattern.
还有红木桌
Black walnut wine table. Metal's cold, ugly.
黑胡桃木餐桌，金属冷酷丑陋
木头温暖、洁净...
Wood's warm, clean, provided by nature.
来自大自然
See a piece of furniture take shape, it's like watching a child grow.
看家俱成形就像看著孩子成长
I asked you a question.
你还没回答我的问题
我们被逼离开英国和法国 但我们到了这里
They threw us out of England, threw us out of France,
but here we are, flourishing really,
很繁荣，真的 只是有一点不方便
except for the minor inconvenience of despising everything about your country.
这张单子上列有五十辆车
On this list you'll find 50 cars... five-zero.
I need all 50 delivered to Long Beach Harbor, pier 14 by 8:00 a.m. Four days from now.
我需要在四天后的早上八点
将它们运到十四号码头
I'm paying $200,000.
我会付二十万
I'm not interested. I'm just here for my brother.
没兴趣，我是来找我弟的
你弟来找我，他的风评很好
Young Kip came to me. He had street cred.
大名鼎鼎的雷曼斐的弟弟
The brother of the notorious Memphis Raines.
所以我两周前雇用他付了一万订金给他
So two weeks ago I hired him and advanced him $10,000.
艾利都说了
Atley told me. If it's about the advance, I can understand your anger.
若是订金的问题，我能了解
欠债就要还钱
The debt has to be settled. Ten grand, from me to you.
这是一万
我还给你
- I wish it was that easy. - I don't see the complication.
真希望有那么简单
我看不出有多复杂
I have four days to deliver 50 cars, and I have no cars.
我四天内要交出五十辆车
但我没车
- Well, that's another problem. - It is another problem, isn't it?
那是你的问题
是啊，不是吗?
It's about me delivering 50 top-end cars because I said I would.
是我要变出这五十辆好车
交不出我就失信于我南美的朋友
Because if I don't, my South American friend goes somewhere else from now on.
生意泡汤，这是耻辱
And that's not good. It's a humiliation.
因为说能交车的笨蛋就是我
Because I'm the asshole who said I could deliver.
我长得像笨蛋吗?
Am I an asshole? Do I look like an asshole?
Yeah.
像
我需要那些车
- I need that paper satisfied. - I'm retired.
我早洗手不斡了我弟弟呢?
And where the hell is my brother?
这也是我做的
I made this as well.
我做的第一个
My first one.
压扁一辆车要八万磅的力量
It takes 80,000 pounds of pressure to crush a car.
奇普?
- Kip? - Who's that?
你是推?
- Memphis. - Oh, shit.
曼斐
该死 你还好吧?
You okay?
Shut it off!
关掉它
- Turn it off! - You've got 30 seconds to consider your options.
你有三十秒可以考虑
- Shut it off! - One: You kill me; they kill you.
关掉
第一，你杀我，他们也会杀你
Your brother dies anyway.
你弟还是死路一条
第二，你骗我接下工作
Two: You lie, you accept the job, you take your brother, you run.
带著你弟远走高飞
I hunt you down, I kill you, I kill your brother, and I kill your mother...
我会找到你，杀了你和你弟
因为被你惹怒 我还会杀了你妈
for the aggravation you've caused me.
第三，你接下工作
Three: You accept the deal, you steal some cars,
偷车赚钱，还能当老大哥
you make some money and you be a big brother.
- Memphis! - 8:00 a.m. Friday morning.
星期五早上8点
The cars are on the boat, or your brother's in the coffin.
交车上船或你老弟进棺材
放我出去，快放我出去
Get me outta here! Somebody get me outta here.
(距最后期限72小时)
Listen, you really don't have to make me anything.
你不需要招待我
你来这里救了我一命
Oh, hey, you come down here.
You saved my ass. It's the least I can do.
我至少该招待你一下
Hey, I heard you were, uh, pumping gas someplace up North or something, right?
听说你在加油站做什么的
跟小孩玩赛车
- Yeah, working with kids. - Oh, really?
冠军
"First place." I remember this.
我记得这个
Oh, yeah, that was... that was a long time ago.
是啊，那是很久以前的事了
What'd you put in it?
这里面是什么?
I don't know.
不知道
满好吃的
It's good.
Ow. Ow. Oh, God.
Does Mom know about any of this?
妈知道这件事吗?
No, no, no, she doesn't, and I don't think she should.
不…她不知道
我不认为她该知道，她很辛苦
You know, she... she works really hard, and this... this...
她不需要知道这些麻烦事
She doesn't need to know about any of this stuff.
一切都在我掌握之中
Look, you know, I got everything under control.
厨房著火了
Kitchen's on fire.
天啊
Uh, man.
曼斐
Hey, Memphis.
见到你真好
It's good to see you.
Haul the cartons over there!
小费
- Hey, Fuzzy. - Aw, shit. What are you doin' here?
你们来干嘛? 我说过我什么都不知道
- I told you I don't know anything. - Yeah, but you're a liar.
对，但你说慌
你们会害我失业的
- You're gonna get me fired, man. - Fired? That's not good. You're on parole, right?
那可不妙，你正在假释期间呢
小费，没人想害你失业 我们只想要点消息
Fuzzy, hey, nobody wants to get you fired.
We just need this information is all.
有人在两周前要一拖拉库高级车
Two weeks ago, a call came in for a lot of top-end cars.
那个人是推?
- And who made that call? - I don't have a clue.
我不知道 好，我们问你老板好了
- Okay. We should go talk to your boss. - Oh, shhh.
The delivery date. I know the delivery date.
我知道交货日
何时?
- And when is that? - Thursday, Friday, end of the week.
周末
Well, you get me a name within 48 hours, or we'll be back.
限你两天内给我个名字
Good to see you, buddy.
真高兴看到你
Thank you.
谢谢
我找雷海伦
I'm looking for Helen Raines.
海伦,有人找你
Helen, some guy's here for you.
谁，他长什么样子?
What guy? What's he look like?
很帅，像你儿子
Like a firecracker. Like your son.
You look so good.
你气色真好
Thank you, Momma. Here. Spring... Spring bouquet.
你也一样，妈
春天的花束
What are you doing here?
你来这被斡嘛?
Well, uh, Atley Jackson came to see me.
杰艾利去找我 跟我谈奇普的事
Told me something about Kip.
要我帮你吗?
Can I help you with one of these?
Okay, that's yours.
跟凯瑟说 搞点咖啡来了个稀客
Tell Castlebeck he's not gonna believe who just walked into the Quality Cafe.
我并不意外
I can't say I'm surprised.
他一直都崇拜你，想变成你
All his life he looked up to you, tried to be you.
我想他成功了
I guess now he is.
怎会这样?我都有寄钱给你们
So why is this happening? I send you guys money.
他认识了一些人，他变了
He... He met some people, and he changed.
他已经不单纯了
He lost that... that sweetness, you know?
好吧
Okay... tell me. How deep in is he?
告诉我
他惹上多大的麻烦?
Deep.
很大
Can you get him out?
你能帮他吗?
那我就得做些事
It means doin' things,
things I told you I'd never do again.
做你叫我别做的事
能怎么做就怎么做吧
Do what it takes, Randall.
你何时回来的?
When did you get into town, Raines?
昨晚 回来干嘛?
- Last night. - Last night? What for?
想看湖人队打球 听说侠客球技炫毙了
I thought I'd catch a Lakers game. Heard we got Shaquille.
Guys wanna go?
想一起去看吗?
- Guess not. - Randall, Randall, Randall, come here.
我猜是不想
小雷，过来
I get this call from this uniform, you know?
是一个制服员警通知我的
Axton. Very nice man. Remembers everything.
他脑筋可灵光了
他说"你猜谁回来了?
This man calls me up, says, "Guess who's back in town?" I say, "Who?"
我说"谁?"
He says, "Randall Raines." I say, "Randall Raines the car thief?"
他说"雷曼斐"
我说"偷车大王?"他说"对"
He says, "Yeah." I say, "Impossible." He says, "No, he's back."
我说"不可能" 他说"我敢跟你赌二百元"...
I say, "No, he's not." He says, "Yes, I will bet you $200 I just saw Randall Raines."
你们真爱抬杠，听着...
- You guys said a lot. Look, Detective... - No, whoa, whoa.
最讽刺的是
What's really, really ironic about this...
二天前… 我们查到十三辆待运的贼车
Two nights ago we snare these 13 fresh stolens waiting for export.
当时，我在想...
At the time I'm thinking, "This feels like Randall Raines."
这感受真像雷曼斐
Now, it didn't have your panache, your, uh, flash,
手法没有你好，也不聪明
但感受就像雷曼斐
but it just felt like Randall Raines.
而你却在这里
And now here you are.
我不知道你在找什么
Look, I don't know what you boys are looking for, but I just got back, okay?
但我刚回来，我家里有事
It was a family emergency. Now, that's the truth.
事实就是如此
Family emergency. Yeah, I got a family emergency too, Randall.
我家里也有事了
我得告诉我老婆 我刚打赌输了二百元
I gotta go tell my woman that I just lost $200 on a stupid deal.
她很凶的
- Mmm, she's mean. - What?
什么?
She can be mean.
她有时会很凶
过来,小雷
Come here. Come here, Randall.
请你拿下眼镜吧
Take those glasses off, Randall. Please, do me a favor.
Six years ago you make a real smart move, you know?
六年前，你很聪明
You retire from a life that's gonna get you busted or killed or maybe even both.
你洗手不干保全性命
但我有机会逮你时不逮你
And I'm thinkin' that not putting you away when I had a chance...
就等于是… 拿自己的前途开玩笑
is like this big bug up the ass of this real impressive career that I've had.
我知道，胜利...
Oh, yeah.
Well, without disappointment, you can't appreciate victory.
本就得来不易
Eleanor tell you that?
伊琳诺告诉你的?
Now, that's hittin' below the belt.
这么说很不公平
Yeah, all right, let me tell you about below the belt, Randall.
我跟你说什么是不公平吧
从现在起 你若违规穿越马路、不看号志
From here on out, if you walk across the street outside of a crosswalk,
if you roll through a stop sign,
或是垃圾分分类不确实...
if you use an aerosol can in a manner other than directed...
我不管 只要你稍一犯错，我就逮你
I mean, I don't care, you make one slip,
and I will put you away for good.
等你出狱，人们早就不用车了
- Okay. - By the time you get out, asshole,
there won't even be cars.
到时我们开的是太空船
We'll all be cruising around in your little, vroom, spaceships.
那真糟
That's gonna suck.
伊琳诺是谁?
Who's Eleanor?
是一辆车
It's a damn car.
不准你再谈我老婆了
And don't ever talk about my wife.
抱歉，奥图在哪?
Excuse me. You know where Otto is?
在喷漆室后面
He's in the back, in the paint shop.
Is that you? About time you came to see me.
是你吗?
你也该来看我了
- I missed you. - Good to see you!
见到你真好
You look great.
你气色很好
- It's good to see you. - You too. Oh, remember my Junie?
见到你真好
记得茱妮吧 茱妮，你好吗?
Hey, Junie. How are you?
我们很好，谢谢
- We're doin' good, thank you. - Good, good.
You look happy.
看来你很幸福
Well, I am happy. I really am.
我是很幸福，真的
So what happened here?
这里是怎么回事?
- What do you mean? - Well, it's nice.
什么意思?这极不错，但…
But the chop shop, the stripped cars, my education.
诉车厂、解体车… 我的学校呢?
怎么回事?
What happened? Hey.
老了，就是这样 我不想再诉解车子了
Old age happened. That's what happened.
Got tired of killing 'em.
接著我想到… 我不是毁灭者，是重生者
You know, I woke up one morning and thought,
"I'm no longer a destroyer. I'm a means of resurrection."
我们修复、重组
Now we restore, we revive.
过来，记得怎么玩吧?
Come here. Remember we used to do this?
过来
- What? - You know. Come here. Okay.
法拉利365GTB一4
It's a Ferrari 365 GTB-4 Daytona.
勒曼大赛，l971年
Le Mans, 1971.
四凸轮轴     Vl2引擎
- Five cam... - That's a V-12.
没错、没错…
V-12, right, right, right, right!
转速到顶点了，转速5500
Here it peaks at 5,500 r.p.m.!
告诉我卡雷蒙的事
- What do you know about Raymond Calitri? - Who?
谁? 卡雷蒙
Raymond Calitri.
Uh, excuse us, sweetness. I'll be right back.
抱歉，我们马上回来
- We can talk here. - No, no, no, no, no. It's all right.
可以在这里讲    不、不…
卡雷蒙
Raymond Calitri.
他是个压榨弱者的豺狼
He's a jackal tearing at the soft belly of our... of our fair town.
And he's an asshole to boot, so be careful.
他也是个混蛋，要小心他
我始说奇普的事了
I heard about Kip. Are you considering a comeback tour?
你想重出江湖?
- Do you think it can be done? - Don't do this to me, okay?
可行吗
别这么对我
Please, please not now.
拜托，不是现在
天啊
Oh, man.
要多少车?
- How many cars? - Fifty.
五十辆
- How many days? - Three.
几天时间?三天
How many in your crew?
有多少人手?
One, but I came here hoping to negotiate for a second.
一个，我来这是想找第二个
不行，不可能的
No way. It can't be done.
你需要时间准备、找目标
I mean, you need time to prep, time to shop. You know that.
一定得成功，他们会杀了他
It has to be. They're gonna kill him.
天啊
Oh, man.
我不该来的
It was a mistake to come here.
You have a great life now. I don't want to upset that.
你过的很好，我不该打扰你
Uh, wait a minute. Uh, hold on.
等等，等一等
看看这里
Look around you.
这些日子以来 我完全相信第二次机会
These days... I'm all about second chances.
我们先打几个电话 事成后再重新出发
So, uh, let's make a few phone calls, and we'll go from there, okay?
Okay.
好
- Don't look at me! Look at the people next to you!
别看我，看旁边的架驶 转弯
That's... Turn the wheel!
靠边、靠边停
Pull over! Pull her the hell over!
混蛋
Asshole!
认真学开车吧
Learn how to drive!
Don't touch nothing. Just...
别碰任何东西
No!
你不会转弯、不会打灯号
You can't negotiate turns. You can't signal properly.
不会保持速度
You can't maintain speed. You can't parallel park. Hell, you can't drive, honey.
不会路边停车
你根本不会开车
Shit, I can't swim. I know I can't.
我不会游泳，我有自知之明
所以我根本不去游泳池
So you know what I do? I stay my black ass outta the pool.
好吧，你…
All right now, just...
拜托…
Can you... Oh! Hello?
Memphis! Hey, how are you?
曼斐，你好吗?
当然…何时?
Sure, sure. When? Okay.
好
- 32969811. - All right. Thanks a lot.
多谢了，兄弟
Donny.
唐尼
绕着街角开，好吗?
Just take it around the block a couple of times, okay?
好
All right.
你好，我找费法阑
Hello. I'm calling for Frankie Fish.
他死了，被人砍死的
Frank's dead, man. Yeah, he got scragged.
抱歉
- I'm sorry. - Uh, yeah, I'm looking for Henry Santoro.
我找桑亨利
He went down to Florida with that asshole Frankie Fish.
他跟那个费法阑去佛罗里达了
叫他把钱还给我
- Tell him I want my money. - I didn't mess with your money.
我没拿你的钱
Yes, ma'am. I'm looking for Dan and Mikey.
我找丹和来基
Both of 'em up to Chino. Doin' a nickel apiece.
他们在蹲苦牢，要蹲五年
我才不告诉你我是谁
Now I'm not so sure I want to tell you who this is.
你敢，混球
- Yeah, try it, asshole. - You sound very busy right now.
你听起来很忙
You sound very, very busy.
真的很忙
Whew. There's only two names left.
只剩两个了
Yeah? Let me see.
让我看是谁
"史芬克、莎薇" 那两个，不可能的
Those two? No way.
没别人了
There's no one else.
你确定?
Are you sure?
你跟他讲 为什么是我?
- You tell him. - Listen, why should I...
是你接的电话 好吧
- Come on! - You were the one who answered the phone.
他又不会说话要怎么讲电括?
- Fine! Fine! - But how's a guy who can't speak gonna take a phone call?
你有电话
You've got a call!
史芬克，是你吗?
Sphinx, is that you?
是你的话就按个钮
Press a button if it's you.
莎薇，你要修刹车?
Sway, you set up this brake job?
对，刹车轴变形了 他开车习惯不好
Yeah. He warped all four rotors.
Must've been ridin' those brakes like an old lady.
好
- That's nice. - Sounds like the left bank's running lean.
听来左边的汽缸有问题
客户服务部在那边
The service department's over there.
能跟你谈谈吗?
- Can I talk to you? - Talk to me? Yeah, sure, talk.
跟我谈?好，谈吧
我回来的原因是…
- The thing of it is, I came back because... - Do you know what time it is?
几点了?
五点半
It's 5:30. I came back because...
我回来的原因是…
I gotta go. I'm late for work.
我上班迟了
You're at work.
你已经在上班了
I got two jobs.
我有两个工作
I have discovered that you have to work twice as hard when it's honest.
我发现要不犯法养活自己就得加倍努力
莎薇，再给我一杯吧?
- Hey, Sway, can I get another shot? - Yep.
你还是那么迷人
Still lookin' amazing.
你倒像卖圣经的推销员
While you look like a Bible salesman.
你得救了
You're healed.
我们能不能自然点?
Can we improvise a little bit?
当然，你在想什么?
Sure. What do you have in mind? Wanna get a little crazy?
后面有辆奥斯摩比
There's a Cutlass 442 in the back we can strip down and shine the hood.
我们可以脱光在引擎盖上打滚 怎样?
- What do you say? - Uh, that's not what I had in mind.
我不是想这个
No?
是我弟弟的事
It's about my brother.
奇普有麻烦了
- Kip's in trouble. - I n trouble?
他搞砸了一庄买卖
- Took a boost, and he blew it. - Shit.
And you got some Italians?
所以你得偷些意大利跑车?
- Five or six. - Right.
五或六辆
It's 50 ladies in 24 hours, $200,000.
二十四小时内弄五十辆 有二十万
我已退出江湖了
Well, I've cleaned up.
我了解，我真不愿意来问你
I understand. I hate to even come here and ask...
莎薇，我的酒呢?
Sway, can I get that drink now, please?
我也去问了其他人
I had to ask a few of the others too, and I feel bad about it, but...
我感觉很不好
- But you had no choice. You had to come here... - Pretty much.
但你别无选择 没错
很抱歉
- I'm sorry. - It's all right.
没关系
我想帮奇普 但我不想再偷车了
I'd love to help Kip, but I-I'm not into the life anymore.
那很好
Well, that's a good thing.
- Yeah. - I'm glad to see you're doing well.
很高兴你过的很好
Sorry, I can't help you.
抱歉我不能帮你
- I'd like to pay for your drink. - That's fine.
我请你吧 好
我的酒呢?
How about that drink?
是啊，酒呢?
Yeah, how about that drink?
姓雷的，雷曼斐
Raines! Memphis Raines, huh?
我认识你吗?
- Do I know you? - Well, you should know me...
你该认识
considering all the business you done screwed up for me in the past, baby.
你搞砸了我所有的买卖
你是强尼毕 没错
- Johnny B. - That's me.
我能为你效劳吗?
What can I do for you?
帮我一个忙
Well, I'm gonna tell you what you can do for me, baby.
今晚就离开长堤
Get out of Long Beach, tonight.
我回来处理家务事
I'll be gone in three days. I'm just here on some family business.
Word on the street says Raymond Calitri hired you and your brother...
传言说…
卡雷蒙有笔大买卖
for a top order, a order that should've went to me.
本来该给我的，他却雇了你
That's not the way it went down, Johnny.
事情不是这样的
Hey! Get away from my car, asshole!
别碰我的车，混球
你有什么遗言吗??
Got somethin' to say before I kill you, fool?
史芬克…
Sphinx. Otto send you?
奥图叫你来的?
爸…
Oh, Dad.
若他在世，我们会做业务员
We'd probably both be working at the dealership if he hadn't died,
就跟普通人一样
just like normal people.
妈的
Shit.
怎么了?
What's the matter with you?
Eh, six years does a lot of different things to people.
六年时间会改变很多事
You know, I don't know where you went, but...
我不知道你去哪了，但…
你来了，跟我谈做普通人
you know, you're in there, you're talking about being normal...
但你以前却不务正业
I mean, you were always the one who was goin' after the easy money.
我偷车不是为了钱
I didn't do it for the money.
我是为了车子
I did it for the cars.
闪亮的海蓝色…
Gleaming in marina blue,
亮桔黄
sunfire yellow,
艳绯红
Marlboro red.
求我带走它们
Begging to be plucked.
我就下手了
And I'd do it.
我偷了她
I'd boost her...
狂飙过棕搁泉
and just blast to Palm Springs,
立刻觉得全身舒畅
instantly feeling better about being me.
And then the next day, it seems like,
后来，不久之后…
我中了枪 我的朋友们也很惨
I'm getting shot at, my friends are dying,
大家都去坐牢了
people are going to jail.
我不喜欢变成这样
I didn't like what I'd become.
是啊，接著你就跑了
Yeah, and then you left,
然后我就没了大哥
and then I didn't have a brother anymore,
现在你却想…
and now you want to give me advice...
教训我
and I don't even know you.
而我根本不了解你
And, you know, I got my own family now, I got my own friends.
我现在有自己的家人了
我有朋友
And you can say what you want about them, but they're loyal.
随你怎么说，但他们很忠实
一犯法，情形也会一样
Well, when you hit the wall, the same thing's gonna happen.
你和你的家人
You and your family...
are either gonna get shot...
不是送命…
or get a five-year jolt at Corcoran.
就是会被送进牢里蹲五年
(汽车窃案防治局)
我们扣留的那三部宝士…
Those Mercedes we impounded? Need those newfangled laser-cut keys.
全都来自德斯进口汽车
Each one's from Dressner Foreign Motors downtown Newport...
里面只有这个赖詹姆有前科
where all the employees are clean, except for him.
因汽车保险金诈骗案坐过牢
James Lakewood. Served a nickel at Folsom for auto insurance fraud.
My gosh, I bet he just neglected to mention that to the people at Dressner Foreign Motors, huh?
我敢说他没跟公司被的人提过
更劲爆的消息是 他跟宝士总公司申请备用车轮
It gets better. Young James there places orders for lost keys...
to the Mercedes home office in Germany.
(距最后期限42小时)
这是清单
The list.
我们开始想办法找车吧…
The list. I guess we gotta start beating the bushes and try to find out where they...
- Whoa! 1967 Shelby GT-500. - I know. I know.
67年野马GT500? 我知道
伊琳诺也在上面?
- You got Eleanor here? - Otto, there's somebody here to see you.
奥图，有人找你
小狗长大了
Oh, the puppy's a big dog now!
- How are you doin'? - Hey there, Kip, what is this... What's that up under there?
奇普，你也会长胡子啊
Hey, Otto, how you doin'?
奥图，好久不见，幸会了
It's a long time. Good to see you.
What are you doin' here, Kip?
你来这干么?
- Well, we actually came to talk about some things. - About what?
我们来谈事情的 谈什么?
你们似乎需要人帮忙
Well, you know, it seems like you guys need a little help,
我们觉得我们可以参与
and we thought that we should participate.
但是妈要你别碰这件事
But I just promised Mom I was getting you out of this.
这庄买卖值一大笔钱
No, no, we're talking about a lot of money here.
什么，钱? 你别想拿走我们的钱
- And if you guys think you're gonna get into our Kool-Aid... - - What? Money?
你这个令人讨厌的小混混
Is that why you think I'm doing this, you inconsiderate little punk!
三个失意的偷车贼…
If you wanna participate, well, then you call Mom and you explain to her...
好，去跟妈说你受到伤害了 两天内才偷不到50辆车
Can you explain how you are gonna steal 50 cars in two days?
Hey. Hey.
这就是我不跟家人合伙的原因
This is why I do not do business with family.
你该考虑一下
I think you should consider this.
不，他不能再犯法了
Oh, come on, Otto, please. No, his criminal career has come to an end.
我们若不能成功，他也死定了
Well, his life will come to an end unless we pull this off.
没有他我们也成不了事 你知道的
How can we do it without them? It can't be done, and you know it.
你们有专长吗?
You guys have any skills at all?
- Please! - Yeah, we have skills.
有，藏镜人是电子专家
We... Mirror Man here, he's an electronics expert.
他有些工具你们根本闻所未闻
You know, he's got some gadgets that... that you old farts probably never heard of.
只要有轮子的东西小飞都能开
You know, uh, Tumbler over here, he can pretty much drive anything with wheels...
有些没轮子的也行
and, you know, some things without wheels.
托比是电脑天才
And, uh, and Toby, he's a computer genius.
他能用电脑做很多事
He's... He does fascinating things with computers.
你用电脑能干嘛?
What exactly can you do with a computer, Toby?
我能入侵监理所的主机
I can hack into the D.M.V. Mainframe.
改变引擎号码
I can change VIN numbers. I can change addresses, registrations.
窜改地址、注册内容
I can do a lot of really tricky stuff. I can.
我能做很多事
好，要做就照我的方法去做
All right, all right. We do this, we do it my way.
听我的指挥行事 不高兴就滚蛋
I run the show. You take your orders from me.
If you have any problems with that, you can leave now.
不，那样很好
No, that's fine. That's fine.
怎么会有个笨小孩在这?
- Well, who is Gilligan here, and what does he do? - Gilligan is actually Freb.
笨小孩叫小佛
- Freb can order pizzas like nobody's business. - What?
他叫披萨的本事一流 什么?
及时送达
- It's true. - Hey, people gotta eat, right?
人都得吃饭吧?
这太过分了
This is outrageous. I want my lawyer.
我要找律即 律师来我才说括
I'm not saying a word till I get a lawyer.
那是个选择 也很合理
All right, James, that's an option.
And frankly, a reasonable one.
你找律师吧
So you call your lawyer, James.
我们会以窃车罪名逮捕你 并起诉你
You tell him you've been arrested on suspicion of grand theft auto.
- We indict you. - He'll bail you out.
他会保你出来 我们就等著法庭见
- And we move on to trial. - Okay, okay.
好吧，好吧
有个小子来找我 说他付五百万一支钥匙
A kid came to me, said he'd pay $500 a key.
所以我申请钥匙
So I put the order forms through, and he picked 'em up a couple days later.
他钱天校再来取货
- What's the kid's name? - We kept it anonymous.
他叫什么?
这是匿名交易
He was a well-built kid. Uh, looks like a boxer.
他体格很好，像个拳击手
你们要我怎么做?
- What do you want me to do? - When he comes back, you call us.
他再来就通知我们
- What says he comes back? - A hunch.
你怎知他会再来?
直觉4
To make the Friday 8:00 a.m. Deadline, you're gonna have to go old school.
要及时完成任务就得照规矩来
行动集中在一个晚上孤注一掷
A one-night boost. Put all your nuts in one basket, okay?
一个晚上，你疯了?
- One night? What, are you crazy? - Yes. No, I'm not crazy.
有更好的计划吗?
- What, do you have like a better plan or something'? - Yeah, you spread it out.
有，分开行动、声动击西
- You play shadow games and shit. - We're on a truncated timetable.
我们没时间
Otto, I'm sorry. Can you just listen to me for one second, all right?
奥图，听我说 我们听见了，声东击西
We heard you, Kip. Shadow games. But what you have to understand...
要是玩声东击西…
is that if you play shadow games, by the second night, the heat is onto you.
条子第二晚就会盯上了
一个晚上行动 等有人报窃案
With a one-night boost, by the time the first car's reported stolen,
车子早装船了
your ship's set sail; it's a surprise attack.
这是偷袭
This is a complicated list, fellas, it really is, okay?
这清单很复杂，真的
其中25辆没问题，不过…
There are 25 that aren't a problem,
这些外国车很难找
but these exotics are tough to find.
新款宝士又要有雷射钥匙
And the new Mercedes, they require laser-cut keys, okay?
我有辨法
- Yeah, I got that covered. - You have that covered?
什么?
- What'd I just say? Yeah, I got it covered. - Yeah.
我说了，我有辨法 没错
All right, all right. Well, then let's get to work.
好，大家开始工作吧
托比，入侵保险资料库
Toby, hack into the insurance database...
设法找车
and find as many cars as you can.
找到希拉蕊、纳塔莉和崔茜了
Yes! I got addresses on Hillary, Natalie and Tracy.
唐尼，到监理所查其他的车
Donny, check the D.M.V.For the remaining cars on the list.
抱歉，答错五题，你没通过
I'm sorry, miss, but you've missed five questions.
- That's a failing. - No!
不
- Next. - No! Why?
不，为什么?
有人跟紧车尾时 当然要开快点啊
You're supposed to go faster when somebody tailgates you.
又见面了
- Ah. Hello again. - Mm-hmm. Here's your list...
你要的二十个车主名字和地址
of the 20 car owners' names and addresses that you requested.
谢啦 总共一百元
- Thank you. - That's $100, please.
一百?
- A hundred dollars? - Well, five dollars a car.
一辆车五元，共二十辆 要计算机吗?
Twenty cars. Would you like a calculator?
以前一辆只要二元 多谢了
It used to be two dollars a car. Thanks a lot.
My name's Roger, sir. May I be of some help?
我是罗杰，需要效劳吗?
怪了，我也叫罗杰
That's funny, my name's Roger. Two Rogers don't make a right.
一山不能容二虎
- Roger, I have a problem. - Yes?
我有个问题 我到洛杉矶三个月了
I've been in L.A. For three months now. I have money, I have taste.
我有财富、品味…
But I'm not on anybody's "A" list,
但我却不受人注意
and Saturday night is the loneliest night of the week for me.
周六晚上更是寂寞
一台法拉利可以改变这一切
- Oh. A Ferrari would certainly change that. - Perhaps. Mmm.
也许吧，但是…
But, you know, this is the one. Yes, yes, yes.
就是这辆，没错
I saw three of these parked outside the local Starbucks this morning,
我今天在咖啡店外就看到了三辆
这让我感觉到 这里太多有钱又放纵的笨蛋了
which tells me only one thing.
There's too many self-indulgent wieners in this city with too much bloody money!
Now, if I was driving...
要是我开着一辆
a 1967275 GTB four-cam...
67年的275GTB…
你就不是笨蛋，是个鉴赏家
You would not be a self-indulgent weiner, sir.
- You'd be a connoisseur. - Precisely.
没错，香槟会从天上洒下
Champagne would fall from the heavens.
大家会争相欢迎我
Doors would open. Velvet ropes would part.
这里没有，但仓库里有一辆
I don't have one here,
however I do have one in the warehouse.
太好了
Superb.
仓库里还有什么车?
What else do you have in the warehouse?
Mm-hmm. All right. Uh-huh.
很好
是车商那里的赖詹姆
That was Mr. Lakewood from the dealership.
那小子今天会去拿三支新钥匙
He says that boxer-looking punk is gonna pick up the keys...
to three new Mercedes today.
车款跟我们扣留的一样
Same make and models as the ones we already got impounded.
好戏上场了
Now we're talkin'.
(长堤港，l4号码头)
葛瑞茜精神号…
The El Spirito de Graciela...
周五早上八点准时开船
sails Friday, 8:00 a.m. Sharp.
将车都放距此45分车程处
We'll target all the cars within 45 minutes of here.
等到车子追踪系统启动时…
By the time their alarm tracking systems are activated,
所有车子早就进货柜了
the cars will already be in these containers.
各位，这是莎薇
Fellas, this is Sway.
别发问，我是来帮奇普的
No questions. I'm here for Kip.
- All right. - All right.
是我，他来了
- It's me. He's here. - The red Chevy Nova?
开红色雪佛阑的?
That's affirmative, sir.
没错
他一走，就把车主地址给我
As soon as he leaves, you call me with the owners' addresses, all right?
我马上把表格拿过去
I'll get those forms right over, sir.
Damn boss. Always on my case.
讨厌的老阎，老爱盯我
里面有三支?谢了
- I got three here? - Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
Huh, Randall Raines, Donny Astricky, Otto Halliwell.
雷曼斐、厄唐尼、哈奥图
要派人盯梢吗?
Should I set up some tails?
Uh-uh. They're too smart for that.
他们太聪明了，那反而坏事
They'll just dump the cars.
不，等他们偷宝士时再下手
No, we'll get them with the Mercedes.
派三组人马盯车主家
Let's set up, uh, three surveillance teams at those addresses.
你尽管动手吧
You go ahead and you make your move, man.
And I will be waiting for you.
我会等著你的
干嘛都用女人的名字?
Why do you call 'em girls' names?
是啊，干嘛这样?
That's a good question. Why do you call 'em girls' names?
这是代号，珍、雪莉…
It's code. You say Jane, you say Shirley, Lucy, Edna,
露西、艾德娜 有人监听就会搞不清楚
and nobody listening on the waves is the wiser.
到手了
Got 'em.
Okay.
好了
All right, we've got the addresses on all 50 ladies. Let's scout 'em.
五十位小姐的地址都有了
去查探清楚吧
她在那里
- There she is. - Nice.
很好
Damn, it's cold up here! They keep these Ferraris refrigerated?
真冷 他们冷藏保存法拉利吗
黑人不喜欢冷
And you know black people don't like cold weather! We're tropical people, man.
我们是热带民族
When this is over, I'm gonna smoke a joint,
斡完这票，我要哈一管
watch two hours of Roots, and I'm gonna kick your ass.
看连续剧"根"再扁你一顿
欢迎参加电视汽车猜谜大赛
Hello, and welcome to TV Car Trivia.
问题一，开73年火鸟的是哪个人?
First question: Who was the driver of a '73 Firebird?
奥图
- Uh, Otto? - Uh, Jim Rockford, Rockford Files.
"洛克擂案"的吉姆洛克
Give me Columbo.
"神探可偷坡
- A Peugeot convertible. - What color?
开标志敞篷车
- Grey. - How'd you know that?
颜色? 灰色
你怎么知道?
'Cause I love that show.
我爱死那影集了
I got three words for all of y'all. Get a life!
送你们三个字"别闹了"
小孩才玩这个游戏
Ah, this is some kiddie shit, Sphinx.
夏威夷之虎牌照上写了什么?
What's on Magnum P.I.'s license plate?
"Robin 1."
"罗宾一号"
Wait. Wasn't Robin that faggoty guy who hung with him?
罗宾是那个娘娘腔吗?
不，那是希金
No, that was Higgins. That was Higgins.
老大加十分
Hey, hey, ten points for our fearless leader.
莎薇，毕比南的三个交通工具
Sway, how 'bout giving us the honor of the Bill Bixby trifecta?
"波长扫描"
He drove a Corvette in The Magician,
"墨西哥人"里开雪佛阑
"庞然大汉":里开福特货卡
A Ford pickup truck in The Incredible Hulk,
在"单亲爸爸求爱记"里 他用双脚走路
and in The Courtship of Eddie's Father, he walked.
- Bingo. - My man.
好了
好家伙
艾尔，有何动静?
Al, tell me something.
没有，连个鬼影都没有
Nothin' doing here, sir. Nobody's showing.
知道了
Copy.
来了辆小货车
Minivan approaching.
幼稚圆没这么晚放学吧
It seems a little late for soccer practice.
Heads up. I think we got some activity right here.
注意，有动静了
那是…看来像是雷奇普
Oh, that is... Looks like it's Kip Raines,
and we got a Randall Raines.
还有雷曼斐
If they take this, we will take them down.
他们一下手，我们就动手
他拿了什么东西出来
He's pulling something out of his pocket. You see that?
照相机，他似乎是在做准备
It's a camera. Looks like he's just doing some homework.
让他去吧，我不想打草惊蛇
All right, let's leave him be.
I don't wanna burn this. They will be back.
他们会回来的
Huh.
我们早上去拜访奥图
You know what? Let's go over to Otto's in the morning.
查探一下，看有什么线索
Kick over some rocks, see what's underneath there.
We saved the best for last.
最好的留在最后
The '67 Shelby Mustang GT-500.
67年的野马GT500
- The GT-500? - Yeah, yeah.
那辆GT500 是啊
There she is.
她在那里
Yep, there's Eleanor.
没错,就是伊琳诺
伊琳诺是曼斐的独角兽
Eleanor is Memphis's unicorn.
什么是独角兽?
- What's a unicorn? - Fabled creature.
传中的动物 有角的马，难以俘获
You know, the horse with the horn, impossible to capture.
那种车…你一想偷它，就会发生事情
It's the one car, no matter how many times you try to boost, something always happens.
这次不会有事的
We're gonna get through this this time, right? It's gonna be smooth...
会很顺利
- What's he doing? - And easy.
他在干嘛?别紧张
He's talkin' to her, man. Tryin' to get reacquainted.
他在跟她说话
重新熟悉，他们有段历史
Done had a rough history. She almost got him killed a couple of times.
她有几次差点害死了他
- I don't want any talking back. - He flipped one on the Harbor freeway.
不争执 在高速公路上翻过车
He went off the Long Beach pier once.
掉进长堤码头一次
A smooth, easy ride.
一次轻松自在的旅程
我们要滑翔
We're just gonna glide.
明晚很重要，我们回家吧
Big night tomorrow, guys. Let's go home.
照好了?   好了
- Did you... Did you get the picture? - Yeah.
明晚见，伊琳诺
See you tomorrow night, Eleanor, with your fine ass.
你屁股长的具俏
要吃点什么吗?
Man, we're almost home. You wanna get something to eat?
我想喝杯巧克力麦芽
I'd like to get a chocolate malt.
快下车
- Hey! - Get out of the car!
快、快…
Go, go, go, go, go!
Why are people shooting at us?
他们干嘛对我们开枪? 我炸了他们的车
'Cause I blew up their car!
这里
Over here!
"野兽"
"Beast."
野欺
Okay, okay.
Oh, shit! Oh, shit!
该死,真该死
Hey!
Oh!
Oh, you... you think it's a game?
你以为这是在玩游戏吗?
Johnny B. Cops, man.
强尼，有条子
I ain't got nothin' but time, baby.
我有的是时间
Oh, man, we're gonna be here all night, man.
我们会整晚待在这
你看，警车
Look! Cop car! Uh-huh.
只要我在这 你就得坐在那，一整晚
Long as I'm in here, you're just gonna sit out there, aren't ya? Aye?
听着，计划是这样
Hey, listen, this is the plan.
那里有辆牵引车
This is what we're gonna do. There's a big rig over there.
外面那台牵引车是你的?
Uh, mister, is that your truck out there, the Big Rig Wrecker?
没错 真酷
- Big Rig Wrecker's mine. - That's cool.
我要去哪学习开它?
What do I gotta do? How do I learn? Where do I go?
去卡车架训班
- Well, you gotta go to truck drivin' school. - Truck dri...
我知道，我是说…
I know, man. I know. But I mean like, um... -
- You boys ready to play a little pin the tail on the donkey?
准备好要绝命大复仇了?
我能请你吃个甜甜圈吗?不，我要走了
- Can I get you a jelly donut or something, man? - No, I'm just gonna go.
我要吃松饼 改天吧
- 'Cause I'm gonna have a waffle. - Maybe next time, though.
我要轰了你
I'm gonna smoke you!
What the hell's going on?
想喝点吗?
Want some of this?
Yeah.
好啊
你们有武器持有证明吗?
- You guys got permits for these weapons? - Oh, man!
(距最后期限24小时)
你们以为我只会叫披萨吗?
So you think I can only get pizzas, huh? Boosted it myself.
我自己斡的
Yeah, yeah, yeah. How'd you get it?
是啊，你怎么到手的?
钥匙就在里面
- Actually, the keys were in it. - Oh, well, that kind of defies the point then, don't it?
造就难怪了
你偷了一辆不在清单上的车
You stole a car that wasn't on the list.
你偷了清单上没列名的车子
You stole a car that wasn't on the list!
你乾脆穿上小丑服去警局
Why didn't you just go to the police station in a red clown suit...
把我们的计划告诉条子吧
and let everybody know what we're doin' here?
什么东西? 不知道
- What have we got? - I don't know.
该死，各位
Shit! Fellas.
拿给我看
- What? - Gimme that. - Check this out.
我看看 拿给我看
- Check this out! - Let me see that. This looks like heroin.
看来像是海洛因? 什么?
- Yeah. - What! - Exactly.
你在哪偷到这辆车的? 中国城
- Where did you get this car? - I n front of some poker parlor in Chinatown.
你想这辆车为何没拔车钥匙?
Did you ever consider why a car in a neighborhood like that...
- would have its keys left in it? - No.
也许没人会笨到偷这辆车
Maybe because nobody in that neighborhood would be stupid enough to rip this car off.
开回去 不行
- All right. Get this shit outta here. Take it back. - No, no. We can't take it back.
把它开走
- Get it outta here! - Will everybody relax for a second?
大家别激勤
Take it back!
把它开走…
开回去
把那玩意给我
I'm comin' after that shit. Gimme that.
No!
看你弄的
Man, I will knock the shit out of you.
我要扁你一顿
等等、等等
- Wait, wait, wait. - Who is it?
是谁?
- Detective Castlebeck. - Oh. Christ.
凯瑟警探
好极了
该死
Goddamn it.
- Hey, hello, Otto. - Detective. Good to see you.
你好，奥图警探，真是幸会
很久不见了 是啊，你气色不错
- Long time. - Yeah. You're lookin' good.
Thank you.
这里在搞什么?
So Randall, what do we got here?
跨世代窃车贼聚会，是吗?
We got a multigenerational gathering of players?
- Is that what we got here? - Right.
唐尼在那里
Here's Donny.
你好啊，唐尼
- How you been, D? - I'm just happy to see you, brother.
很高兴见到你
Yeah. I gotta tell you, Randall. Seeing you here, Otto, Donny,
曼斐，我得说…
看到你、奥图和唐尼
makes me feel almost nostalgic.
让我几乎想起从前
Kind of like a big reunion.
我们是在重聚
别走 我们等会要烤甜点、唱歌呢
You should stick around, 'cause a little later we're gonna...
make s'mores and sing "Kumbayah."
这是什么?
- What is this? - What? They call this a Cadillac.
这个 这是凯迪拉克
Yeah.
它怎么了?
- What's wrong with it, Otto? - Rest...
它需要翻修   怎么了?
- Needs restoration. - What?
烤漆
- Brightening. - Otto.
奥图，你有辆39年的福特
- You got a '39 Ford right there. - That's a pretty car.
那辆车很棒吧?
- Isn't that a nice car? - Yeah. Right here you got a '53 Fiat Vignale.
还有53年的飞稚特
真美的车
Now, these are beautiful cars, Otto. And here we got a '83 Cadillac Eldorado.
却还有辆83年凯迪拉克?
- Yeah. - I mean, who the hell pays...
谁会付钱…
to brighten up a Cadillac Eldorado?
帮凯迪拉克重新烤漆?
我想车主是对它有感情 没别的了
I think it holds a certain sentimental value, you know.
Nothing more.
帮我查个车牌
Run me down a tag.
License 3-2-9-H-R-O.
牌照号码329HRO
暗红色的凯迪拉克
That is Harold, Randall, Otto, burgundy Cadillac.
你不相信我们改过向善了?
No faith in our newfound goodness, Detective? Huh?
警察只相信证据，你知道的
Task force runs on statistics and numbers, Otto. You know that.
曼斐，这是奇普?
- Randall, this Kip? - That's my brother.
没错
He's all grown up.
他长大成人了
One-Baker-eleven, Pacific Division...
lBll
three-two-niner, Harold, Randall, Otto.
329HRO
目前无通报、未失窃
No wants, no warrants at this time. D.M.V.Not on file.
知道了，谢谢
Copy that. Thank you.
我知道你在想什么
See, I know what you're doin'. I know.
你在想，无通报…
You're thinkin' there's no want, but that I stripped its guts...
我就会把它解体出售
and crated her up, right?
你真的都这么做?
Is that what you did, Randall?
我没有，算了
No. I didn't do it. You know, you're trying to hurt my feelings? Fine.
去试车，飙一下吧
You know what? Go ahead. Do it. Let her rip.
好好催它 我会的
- Go ahead, rev it up. - All right, goddamn it. I will.
便宜卖你
Sell it to you cheap.
83年开始有自动导航装置
Yeah. '83. First year they put the auto-ride control on these boys.
我不知道 你现在可能比我还懂车呢
Oh, I don't know. You probably know more about cars at this point than I do.
你连我都比不上了? 你只是知识比我强
- You slippin' on me, Randall? - No, it's just your knowledge overwhelms me.
引擎声音很棒
- It's got a real nice-sounding engine. Right, Otto? - Four point one liter.
4l00CC
- Digital fuel injection? - You got it. You're the man.
数位喷射引擎 没错，你真懂
再来、再来
Give it some more. Give it some more.
很好
- Yeah, that's it! - Go, go!
再催、再催
你真强
Baby, don't be so mean! Yeah, that's it!
感受真好 弄坏了你可要赔
- Oh, that was good. - Yeah, you break it, you buy it, my friend.
Yeah, she got some power goin' on.
她的马力真不错
All right.
好吧
改天兄了
I'll catch you later.
今晚行动 你怎么知道?
- It's on for tonight. - How do you know?
他们定好今晚的联络代号了
They got the call signs on all the units working tonight.
你想用这干嘛?
- Wh-What were you gonna do with this? - I was gonna bonk him.
打昏他
Bonk? For the next 24 hours,
打昏?
接下来的二十四小时 你们无权做任何决定
all your decision-making privileges have been removed!
'懂了吗?
- You got it? - Got it. - Yeah, that's cool.
'懂了 好
Obviously they're onto us. He's sniffin' real close.
条子盯上了，他差点就查到了
今晚要有任何不对劲
If anything tonight appears out of place,
就停止行动、离开现场
I want you to cut bait, get out of there and walk away.
把那辆车解决掉
And get rid of this goddamn car!
什么事，奇普?
- What's up, Kip? - Bobby, what are you doin'?
你在干嘛?
You think you're comin' with us, but you're not.
你不能跟我们去
我也是一份子，我要去
What are you talkin' about, man? I'm part of the team. I get to go.
你会被捕或送命的，别蠢了
No, no, wake up. Gonna end up in the jail or the morgue or some shit. Don't be stupid.
那我该做什么?
What am I supposed to do?
需要橡胶手套吗?
Did you see a box of rubber gloves here, man?
不用，这是高科技时代，你看
Gloves? Man, you don't need gloves. This is the new age. Check this out.
这是什么?
- What is this? - Let me just see that big claw you call a hand.
把你的大熊掌仲过来
这不是果冻，别乱吃
That's not doughnut jelly, so don't eat it.
你的新指纹，猫王还魂了
Your new fingerprints. Elvis is back.
Hmm.
- Boy got skills, right? - Yeah, you do.
我一身本事
没错
Look like a little ghetto Smurf.
具像长了厚茧
我是坏胚子
I am a bad man.
谢了
Thanks. Thanks for doin' this.
谢谢你们参与
集中注意力，想清楚
Keep it real. Think slow.
我们会成功的
We should get through it just fine.
"飘泊车手"唐尼
"Low Rider," Donny. Donny? "Low Rider."
唐尼"飘泊车手"?
上路吧
Okay, let's ride.
(距最后期限l2小时)
Oh! Shit.
该死
把手电筒给我
Gimme that torch. Aha!
你看，看我的吧
I tell you, I'm the man. Now, where does this go?
得想辨法打开它
Find a way to get in here. Get this...
由我主导行动 你再这样我就-…
I tell you, I'm runnin' this shit! You do that again, I will kick...
没事，我不是针对你
Cool, man. You don't have to take it so damn personal.
Ah. Everything is perfect.
一切顺利
哈罗，小姐们
Hello, ladies. Always was a sucker for a redhead.
我就是没辨法抗拒红色
Let's go. Come on, move, move! Go, go!
动手吧，快点
我知道你懂法拉利，动手吧
Work your magic, baby. I know you know Ferraris. Work your magic.
这女孩真有本事
- Girl got skill.
你还好吧?
You all right?
能成功吗?
- You think we're gonna make it? - I don't know. It's too early to tell.
现在还不知道
黛安、翠西、娜汀… 还有罗丝都上路了
Diana, Tricia, Nadine and Rose are on their way.
斡的好
Good goin', guys.
艾尔，报告动静
Al, tell me something.
第二组，抱歉...
Unit two. Sorry, sir. Nothing yet.
大鸟，回来
没动静
Son of a bitch.
混蛋
I know you're not parking right in front of me.
你不能把车停在我前面
我什么都看不到了
Oh, no. I can't see a damn thing.
好吧，我们得移一下
All right. We gotta move.
(距最后期限lO小时)
You ever feel bad about any of this?
你偷车会有罪恶感吗? 没有
Hell, no. I'm Robin Hood, man. I rob from the rich and give to the needy.
我是罗宾汉，我劫富济贫
该死
Damn. Donny!
唐尼 来了、来了
I got you. I got you.
你是指穷人
- You mean the poor. - Cutters.
钳子     钳子
Cutters.
No, like I said, the needy.
不，是需要的人
兄弟，我们需要这辆车
'Cause, brother, we need this car.
你好啊，朋友?
- What's up, Doc? - You're new, aren't ya?
你是新来的 你怎么知道?
- Yeah. How can you tell? - Now, listen, son. You take real good care of this car,
听着，顾好这辆车
and I'll take care of you.
我就会照顾你
Tell you what. Save it. You get another one of these suits, all right?
留着买套新西装吧
上帝保佑你
- God bless you, son. - You need a fashion counselor.
你需要造型顾问
All right, babe. I ain't here for the door. I here for the car. Get your big ass out.
我只负责泊车，不负责开门 大屁股快下车
下车，你看什么看?
- Hmm? - Out! What are you lookin' at?
妈的，真是易如反掌
- Hey, man, that was as easy as pie. - I'm a veteran, son.
我是老手
Get outta the car, bitch, or I'll blow your brains out!
下车，不然我开枪了
- You gotta be shittin' me. - I will shoot you, damn it!
别用玩笑了
我会开枪的
Damn!
该死
You lazy, half-ass bully! Any asshole can pull a gun on somebody!
懒惰无能的家伙
白痴也会用枪
You don't know the first thing about stealin' a car! Boy, I...
你根本不懂偷车，怎么?
去拜师吧
You need a role model!
史黛西
Stacy.
夏蓉
Shannon.
罗拉
Laura.
琳赛
Lindsay.
芮秋
Rachel.
快看
Hey. Check this out.
他回来了
J.J., he's back. But he's smart. He watches his ass.
他很聪明，也很小心
Just hold our positions. If he rolls,
别妄动
他一下手，你就跟上去
- you follow him out. - Copy that.
知道了
他在干嘛?
What's he doin'? What... What are you doing?
你在干嘛?
我们也许该摇下车窗跟他挥手
We might as well roll down our windows and wave.
小杰，你跟着他 知道了
- J.J., you tail him. All right? - Copy that.
我们走
Let's go.
祝好运
- Good luck. - Piece of cake.
没问题
第一组，这是第二组 唐尼来了
Unit one, this is unit two. Astricky has landed.
他们一下手就逮捕
If they roll, we take them down.
昨晚那车停在四间房子之外 现在却只隔两间了
Last night that van was parked four houses down. Now it's only two.
我们有同伴了
- We got company. - Shit.
该死
He's at the car.
他到车旁了
Bird, come back.
第一组准备
- Stand by, unit one. - What?
怎么了? 你在哪里?
- Where are you? - Where do you think I am?
你以为我在哪?
I'm at the casino, picking up pit boss's lady. What do you want?
在赌场外，正要接老阎的女人
那女的有问题
- The ladies are dirty. Walk away. The ladies are dirty. - What?
快走，那女的有问题 什么?
大家快回车库
I want everybody to get back to the garage now.
Oh, so she's havin' a baby right now?
她要生了?
I guess I better get to the hospital then, huh?
我得快点赶到医院
Something's got him spooked.
有事情吓到他了
My wife is havin' a baby. Gotta get...
我老婆要生了
这不是我的车，我的车在那边
I'm nervous! This ain't even my car! Way over here...
他万开车子了
He's heading away from the vehicle.
I see you.
我看到你了
开进去里面
Pull in over there.
- Hello. This is unit two. I lost them.
这是第二组，我跟丢了
该去找小费谈谈了
All right, it's time to talk to Fuzzy again.
你看
Check this out. Laser-encoded keys that send a message to a receiver...
雷射钥匙送出讯号
inside the car.
钥匙从哪来的?
You wanna tell me what you're doin' with these?
上周偷车时搭上的
Yeah. These are from last week. These are from the other boost.
是谁?
Who is it?
- The keys, the keys, the keys! - Take it easy!
怎么了?
- Now gimme this! - What happened? What happened?
这些钥匙哪来的? 怎么了?
- Where'd you get these from? - What's the problem?
那些宝士有人监视
The Mercedes are dirty! There's surveillance vans all over them.
钥匙哪来的?
- Where'd they come from? - Whoa. My guy in Southland. The same guy I used last time.
南部的朋友，我以前找过他
- Same guy I used before. - Before when?
什么以前?
- When we... When we took the other cars. - Other Mercedes.
我们偷其他车时 其他的宝士
- Christ. - Castlebeck.
是凯瑟
He got to one of the guys at the dealership, and he turned him. That's what happened.
他找到车商的人，逼他合作
只剩八小时了
Eight hours left.
我们要继续站在这里开会吗?
So what, we're gonna stand around and have a meeting? Wh-What's goin' on?
曼斐
Memphis, maybe it's time for us to start thinking about...
也许我们该把这些孩子送走
- how to get these young kids out of town, 'cause...
拜托，你知道…
没有宝士，偷其他车也没用
If there's no Mercedes, there's no point in boosting any other cars. You hear me?
完了
- That's it. - 47 is not 50, Memphis. You know that's what he'll say.
他会说四十七辆不等于五十辆
Yeah.
曼斐，我们还有上回偷到的宝士车钥匙
Hey, Memphis. You know, we still have the Mercedes keys from the last boost.
那些车被警方扣留了
Hey! Those cars are at the police impound.
你要我们去那里偷车吗?
Okay? The police impound. You want us to go there and start stealin' cars?
没错
- Yeah. - Yeah, let's do it. - You're crazy.
你疯了?
- We're gonna get hectic. Let's go. - No, Memphis, no. Don't do this.
振作起来，那些钥匙呢? 不行
我看起来不可疑吧?
Hey, Sphinx, I don't look suspicious, do I, man?
奥图，你的狗把钥匙吃了
Otto, man, I think that your dog ate the keys.
它通常都吃车牌的，你确定?
He usually goes for the license plates.
- Are you sure? - What? Wait a minute. The dog ate the keys?
等等，狗吃了钥匙? 是啊
- Yes. How you gonna get them out?
要怎么才弄得出钥匙? 这不好笑
- Not funny. - I'm...
想都别想
- Hey, hey, don't even think about it, Sphinx.
没关系
It's all right.
Say, uh, Toby,
托比，设法去弄点…
go see if you can get some, uh, Alpo, and get some Ex-lax.
狗罐头跟泻药
不会吧
- No way, man. - Bad dog!
坏狗狗
- Let's get back to work.
工作吧
Hey! Open the door.
开门
- Ah, Jesus. - Hurry up. Hurry up.
快点
别闹了，摇滚巨星 天啊
- End it, rock star. Get in. - Jesus Christ.
怎么，你们还要什么?
Now what, man? What else?
小费，你都没给我报讯 现在我们得留在这…
Fuzzy, you never called me. So now we gotta stay down here...
除非你说出你所知道的一切
till you tell me everything you know.
我都说了
I... I told you everything I know. I know that,
我说过我只知道这些的
because I said, "This is everything I know."
戴警探
Detective Drycoff, does it seem like the suspect is violating his parole right now?
你想嫌犯是否违反假释?
当然，凯瑟警探
Why, yes, Detective Castlebeck, if by violating his parole...
他拒绝跟执法人员合作
you mean failing to cooperate with a law enforcement officer.
我在偷车贼退休之家学的
A little trick I learned in the car thief retirement home.
帮我拿着好吗?
Can you hold this?
我没有拒绝合作，我只是…
No, no, no. I'm not failing to cooperate. It's just that...
好吧、好吧
Y-Y-Yeah. Okay. Okay. Uh, word has it...
传说雷奇普接下买卖部搞砸了
that Kip Raines took the job and he screwed up. Uh, he screwed up pretty bad.
糟糕透了
And who put out the order for the job?
谁的买卖?
卡雷蒙
It's Raymond Calitri's order.
Nice.
干的好
快、快啊
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
Yes.
好耶
还剩六小时 那只狗拉了没?
We have six hours left. Has the dog done its business yet?
托比和小佛去它了
Toby and Freb are walking him right now.
- He's not gonna go it. It's not gonna happen, man.
它不会拉的，钥匙拿不到了
快啊，狗狗
Come on, dog. What's wrong, Hemi? Poop, dog.
怎么了，快拉啊?
这一定是女人的车
- It had to be a girl car. - Girl car, what kind of a girl drives a Hemi 'Cuda?
女人的车? 女人怎会开这种车
我证明给你看
I'll show you.
唇膏?
Lipstick?
颜色跟车子很配
Matches the car.
接下来呢，腮红、睫毛膏?
- What's next? Blush? Mascara? - Next time...
下回，我要穿皮衣、高跟鞋 还有粉红色内衣
I'll pull out the, uh, leather and high heels and pink underwear for you.
皮衣、高跟鞋和粉红色内衣
- Leather, high heels and pink underwear. - Pink underwear.
我喜欢粉红色内衣，我喜欢
- Pink underwear works. Pink underwear works.
卡雷蒙因杀人在南伦敦服过刑
Raymond Vincent Calitri did five years in South London for manslaughter.
98年移民
- He immigrated in '98. - Look at this.
你看… 放高利贷、勒索、收售贼物
Loan shark and extortion, fencing. Ha. His front's a salvage yard.
他真是前科累累
得等他们上床才行
Gonna have to wait it out.
So, you seeing anybody?
你有对象吗?
没有
No. No, I had a girl once.
我以前有个女友
她很棒
- She was great. - Mmm. So if she was so great, why'd you leave her?
她要是那么棒，为何万开她?
我有要你跟我一起走
I did ask you to come with me.
不，你是要我变成另一个人
No, you asked me to be a different person.
我不想看到有人受伤
I didn't want to see people get hurt. I just wanted you to slow down.
我只是要你放慢脚步
Well, I couldn't.
我没办法，我还没准备好
'Cause I wasn't ready.
你现在很循规蹈矩了
- You're straight now. - Yeah, I am.
因为没有你，一切都变了
'Cause it wasn't the same without you.
抱歉
- Excuse me, gentlemen. - Hey, asshole. I was reading that.
我还在看，混蛋
- Watch your mouth, kid. - What's goin' on?
说话小心点
- This is a homicide file from a homicide investigation. - All right.
这是一庄凶杀案的档案
等了三个月法官才授权监听
It took us three months to get a magistrate to give us a wiretap on 'em.
没有任何部门，包话肃窃局
No other division, including GRAB, can go near his person, residence or place of business.
可以接近他、他家或他公司
懂了吧，我告诉你们吧…
All right? Got it? Let me tell you guys something.
All right. Raymond Calitri is going down for murder one. Boneheads.
卡雷蒙会以一级谋杀罪起拆
谁鸟什么窃车案啊?
Who gives a shit about grand theft auto? Really.
我看不下去了
I can't watch this.
快点，快上啊
Come on, come on, come on. Get it on. Get it over with.
你觉得哪一样比较刺激… 做爱还是偷车?
What do you think is more exciting, having sex, or stealing cars?
做爱还是偷车?
Having sex or boosting cars?
Um. Ooh!
Uh.
Well, uh, how about, uh...
一边偷车… 一边做爱如何?
having sex while boosting cars?
说的好
God, that's a good line.
Oh, doesn't work on a lot of girls, though.
但对很多女人都没用
我只是随口说说…
I just blurted it out. I'm s...
但你还没回答
But you haven't answered the question.
Well, you see, the problem is,
问题是…
how do you get over the shifter?
排档杆卡在中间
- Oh. Oh, right. 'Cause the, uh... - Because it gets in the way.
是啊，它… 刚好挡住
你不会想弄坏同步装置吧?
Because you wouldn't want to disrupt the, uh, synchromesh. Right?
或进气阀门…
Or the throttle linkage.
主汽缸万合器…
The clutch master cylinder.
Double overhead cam shaft.
双凸轮轴
- I can't do this. - Wait, wait. Just straight in-line six,
我没办法
等等、等等
用同轴引擎、韦伯化油器
triple Weber carburetors...
连结到彼此的身上
Bolted to each other's body structures.
该动手了
Oh, it's time to work.
刹车踩的好
Good brakes. Good brakes too.
没有动静
- There's nothin' happening. - Maybe he's got indigestion.
也许它消化不良
- Well, dude, we'll give him some more Ex-lax. - He already ate two.
再多喂它一点泻药 它已经吃两颗了
小鬼
- Hey, little man. - Oh, man.
糟糕
I thought I told you this is our turf. What, you wanna make a move?
我说过这是我们的地盘了
你想开战吗?
We don't want anything to do with your turf.
我们不要你的地盘
Something wrong with where we live?
不喜欢我们住的地方吗?
Oh, no, it's cool for you. I mean, it's just not for us.
你们住很好，但不适合我们
你自以为比我们优秀吗?
Oh, so now you think you're better than us or something, huh?
也许我们该砍死你
- Maybe we should cut you up, doll? - Um...
兄弟，钥匙
- Dude, the keys. Freb. - Excuse me a second, guys.
恕我失陪
天啊
Man!
我要吐了
- Aw, I'm gonna throw up, dog! - Man, that's disgusting.
真恶心
What kind of pervert gets their jollies off playing with dog shit?
只有变态会玩狗大便
快看，三支都找到了
Look, man! I got 'em. All three, man.
你们真是有病
- You guys are sick. - I got 'em!
我找到了
(距最后期限6小时)
(洛城警局车辆保管场)
醒醒，看一下这个
Wake up, man. Check this out.
我每回开富豪车去比佛利山
Every time I drive my Volvo in Beverly Hills, they tow the shit.
就会被拖吊
我们这里没富豪车
- We ain't got any Volvos here. - There is a Volvo here. I know.
你们有，条子说的
- They told me... - Wait a minute. Wait, wait.
等等 我告诉你，这里没有富豪车
What I'm tryin' to tell you is, there ain't no Volvos here.
查一下，找找我的富豪车
Then get in your book, do something. Find my damn Volvo!
史芬克、莎薇
Sphinx. Sway.
一定登记在里面，查一下
It's got to be somewhere in there. Check it out, man.
这里什么都没有，你看
Wait, wait. There's nothing here. Look.
还有一个保管场…
- There's another one... - No, no! Uh-uh, hey! Tell you what, look at this.
你看这个
看着她…她法力条边…
Look at her.
抱歉，我不该在这里的
Look, I'm sorry. I don't even need to be out here.
有人找我
Hey, uh... I got a midget pagin' me right now.
我得走了，时间就是金钱
- Wait... - I gotta get outta here. Hey, time is money.
This is the worst damn day of my life.
这是我这辈子最糟的一天
凯瑟警探，仓库里的… 玻璃碎片是紫外线灯泡碎片
"Detective Castlebeck. Glass shards...
"from the warehouse from a black light bulb...
五金行都有卖
available at any local hardware store."
All right.
干嘛在长堤仓库…
What the hell is a black light bulb doin' in a...
用紫外线灯泡?
warehouse in Long Beach?
跟我来
Come with me.
看到吗?
- See this glass right here? - Let me guess.
我猜猜看，紫外线?
- Black light? - Black light.
紫外线 检查那面墙，我检查这面
Take that wall. I'll take this wall.
记得70年代吧?
- Remember the seventies? - Too young, thank God.
我还很小，感谢上帝
那时紫外线灯管很流行
Black lights were all the rage back then.
还有紫外线墨水、魔术笔
You know, they had this ink, these magic markers.
要在紫外线照射下才看的到
Only show up under black light.
你若有资讯不想让人知道
So if you got a whole lot of information that you don't want anybody to have...
像是偷车清单… 没错
- Like a shopping list of cars? - There you go. Whoa!
好耶、好耶
Yes. Yes!
清单在这里
Here is our list.
数量很大 我们条法完全掌握
That's a big list. We can't handle all these cars.
也并不需要，我们只要…
Maybe we don't have to. I'd say where let's concentrate on the rarest ones,
注意稀有的车款
and let's just hope for some luck.
找人监视这几辆
Let's get somebody on this right here. You and I will take this one right her.
我们盯这辆：67年的野马
'67 Shelby Mustang.
城里应该很少有
- Can't be but a few of these in town. - Yeah.
你怎么知道他还没偷走它?
But how do you know he hasn't already stolen it?
我了解他，他会把它留到最后
Oh, if I know our boy, I believe he'll leave this one till last.
为什么?他怕它
- Why? - He's afraid of it.
(距最后期限三小时)
各位
Yo, guys. It's me.
天啊，你在干嘛?
- Oh, man. What are you doing? - I want to come along with you guys on a boost.
我要参与行动
Come on. Let's go. Later. Come on.
待会再说，走吧
快、快、快
Go, go, go.
What's the matter with you? Come on!
你是怎么回事?
Hey, call security! Someone's stealing the car!
通知保安，有人偷车
快走，你在干嘛?
- Go, go, go! - What are you doing?
Whoa. I ought to leave your ass. You know that? What's the matter with you?
我本想丢下你不管的 你是怎么回事?
你看，牌照上写着"大蛇
Hey, Sphinx. Check this out. Home boy got "Snake" on the license plate.
大蛇主明天得搭公车了
Well, Snake will have to slither his ass all the way to the bus stop in the morning.
Police officers. We need to check the lot for a car.
警察，我们要查看一辆车
去吧
Go ahead.
来点开车音乐吧
Check this out, man. Here's some low-ridin' music.
跟你之前放的蠢歌不太一样
It's a little bit different than that cracker shit you used to be playin'. Check this out.
你喜欢的
You like that. You feelin' it? Are you feelin' it?
喜欢吗?我就知道你会喜欢
I know you're feelin' it.
蛇，快弄走它
Oh! Snake! Get this thing off me!
蛇…
Snake! Snake! Snake!
快把它弄走
Get this thing off me, man! It's a snake!
有蛇
It's tryin' to kill me, man! Get this thing off me!
它想害死我，快弄走它
它们最喜欢害黑人兄弟了
Somebody always want to kill a brother. Man, this is wrong.
你在干嘛，把蛇弄走
What the hell are you doing? Get the snake!
踩刹车 我有踩啊
- Use the brakes! - I am!
This snake is crawlin' up my ass, man!
这条蛇爬上我的屁眼了
This snake is up my ass!
它爬上来了
它会吃掉我的大便
This snake gonna swallow my shit!
(距最后期限2小时)
老天，我真爱那辆车
God, I love that car. All right. Two ladies, home safe.
两位小姐平安到家了
He's tucking in Vanessa, and Bernadine just took me for a ride.
他送雯妮莎上床
蓓娜汀则和我有了一腿
What's the count?
多少了?
- Forty-eight. - Yes!
四十八辆
好耶
But Mirror and Sphinx had some unexpected visitors.
藏镜人和史芬克遇到不速之客
是凯瑟? 我想是吧
- Castlebeck? - I think so.
一切都还好吧? 很好
- Everything cool? - Yeah, yeah, they're fine.
他们跟唐尼和小佛在奥图那里
They're on their way back to Otto's. Donny and Freb are already there.
奇普和小飞呢?
- What about Kip and Tumbler? - No word yet.
还没有消息
Lost in suburbia. Hell, where are we?
在鬼郊区迷路，我们在哪?
- What do you mean? You don't know where you're going? - Which way is out?
你迷路了?
I don't know where I am. Everything looks the same to me.
怎么出去? 附近全都长的一样
你不知道我们在哪?
You don't know where you're going?
是条子 不，是保安
- That is a cop. - No, it's not. That's rent-a-cop.
慢一点 他要回转了
- Slow down. Slow down. - He's pulling a U-turn.
天啊，我们有麻烦了
Oh, man, we're in big trouble.
被窃的凯迪拉克休旅车…
In pursuit of stolen Cadillac S.U.V.,
在莫瑞街上往西行驶
traveling west on Murray Drive.
路障 小心
- Roadblock, Kip. Oh, shit. - Look out for the roadblock! - Go, go!
枪
快走
Go!
- Oh, man. - Motherfucker.
天啊
- Oh, shit. Oh, shit. - I need help, man.
该死、真该死
- What? - He's been shot! Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
怎么回事?
他中枪了
别碰
- Don't touch me! - We need to go to the hospital, man!
快去医院
People ask questions in hospitals, Kip.
医院会盘问我们的 快去
- Go to the hospital! - You should use your head. We're in a stolen car!
想清楚，我们开着贼车
Now, this does not look good.
情况不妙
You're gonna be all right.
不会有事的
- Oh, man! - What happened?
怎么回事? 我们碰到保安人员
- We ran into security patrol. - He hid in the van. We didn't know he was there.
他躲在车里
We gotta get you to a doctor, private. I know just where to go.
我们会帮你找私人医生 把他扶进我车里
- Let's get him to a car. - No! Ow!
躺在后座
Lie in the back. Lie down in the back.
到后座躺下
Tumbler, you and Kip take the last van back to Otto's.
小飞，你和奇普把车开给奥图
- You all right? - Yeah, go.
你干嘛?
- What are you doin'? - I'm goin' with him.
我要跟他一起去
要是出事… 走吧
- If something should go wrong, just... - Let's go!
我会照料他的
I'll take care of him, man.
做个了结吧
Let's finish this.
(野马GT500)
(伊琳诺)
(距最后期限l小时)
怎么了?
- What's up? - What's the story with that Humvee?
悍马车怎样了 没了
- Gone. - Cadillac?
凯迪拉克? 一样，我们要去哪?
The same. Where are we goin'?
这附近唯一一辆67年野马
The only '67 Shelby in the area is registered...
在长堤国际名郊
at a place called the International Towers in Long Beach.
我们去长堤吧
Let's go to Long Beach.
我知道我们有段过去，伊琳诺
I know we got a history, Eleanor,
and that that history has not been great, but I promise...
那段过去并不好，但我保证…
你照料我，我也会照料你
you take care of me, I'll take care of you.
该死
Shit.
简单还是难走的路
The easy way or the hard way, Raines. Easy way or the hard way?
- Hey! - I think he's choosin' the hard way.
我想他选难走的那条路
All right.
好吧
这是lBll 追踪67年灰色野马
One-Baker-eleven. I n pursuit of '67 Ford Mustang, gray.
"请勿进入"耶 你注意到了?
- That sign said "Do Not Enter." - Yeah. You noticed, huh?
天啊 坐稳了
- Jesus! - Keep your pants on.
嫌犯在第四街向东前进
Suspect now traveling east on Fourth Street.
更正，缅因街向北前进
Correction. Make that north on Main.
走开 退后
Move! Get the fuck... Just move!
走开啊
别挡路
Get out of there!
你想让我发狂?
Oh, you wanna get crazy with me!
Come on, boy.
来吧
这是lBll 第三组在第七街口发生车祸
One-Baker-eleven. Unit three involved in a T.A. At St. Vincent's and Seventh.
全体注意 目标进入高速公路旁防洪道
All units, pursuit has entered flood control adjacent to 710 freeway.
空中小组呢?
- Where's that air unit? - Requesting air unit. Same location.
请求空中支援
Al飞跃目标
Air One. We're over the pursuit.
嫌犯时速90哩向南飞驰
Suspect traveling southbound at 90 miles an hour.
跟着他 我紧跟着他
- Stay with him, Air One. - I'm all over him.
"注入一氧化氮"
"动啊，宝贝"
- Suspect has increased speed to 120. - Maintain visual, Air One.
嫌犯加速至l20哩
保持目标距万
140 miles an hour.
时速l40哩
别跟丢了
- Do not lose him. - This is an A-Star, sir, not an Apache.
这又不是阿帕契
One-fifty. One-sixty.
150，l60
他跑了
- He's gone. - God!
天啊
- Man, this guy can drive. - What, what?
这家伙真会开车
什么? 也许是车子的关系吧
It's probably mostly the car.
几点了?
Hey, what time is it?
七点半
7:30.
我想我得把你送出城去了
I think I'm gonna have to get you out of town or something.
你哥是世上最棒的偷车贼
Your brother's the best boost in the world, but I don't know if he's gonna make this one.
但他这回可能不会成功了
我不像我哥，我不会抛弃朋友
I'm not like my brother, you know. I just don't abandon my friends.
我真该海扁你一顿
Oh, man. I ought to smack you silly, boy.
你以为你哥跑了?
You know, your brother ran away, is that what you think?
认清真相吧
You better get your story straight.
那就说啊，把真相告诉我
Well, go on then. Straighten it out.
你妈叫他走的
Your mother told him to go.
她知道要是曼斐留下
She knew if Memphis stayed, you were gonna walk his line.
你就会步他后尘
You were gonna join his crew.
你会加入他，所以她叫他走
But she told him to pick up and go.
他走了，以为这样针你最好
And he did, thinkin' it was best for you.
他为了你…万开我们
He left all of us. For you.
那其实没什么大不了
Guess it wasn't that big a deal for him though, really.
抛下一切并不是多大的牺牲
Wasn't that big a sacrifice, leavin' everything he'd ever known behind.
六年后，人生真奇妙…
And six years later, ain't life grand?
你还是成了一个偷车贼
You became a car boost anyway. How about that?
怎么样?
我给他打了镇静剂，他睡了
I sedated him. He's sleeping.
他不会有事的
He's gonna be just fine.
(距最后期限二十五分钟)
只是小伤，伊琳诺 可以修好的
It's just a scratch, Eleanor. It can be fixed.
No, no, no, don't.
不…别这样，别这么对我
Don't do this to me. Don't... Don't start with me.
不、不要…快启动
Don't... No, no... No, start!
启动啊，拜托，启动
Start, start, start. Come on. Come on.
我需要你，伊琳诺
I need you, Eleanor. I need you now, now.
我现在就需要你
All units, be advised.
全体注意
Suspect vehicle headed south on Henry Ford Boulevard.
嫌犯在福特大道上向南前进
我们该在海洋街拦下他
We should hit him at Ocean Avenue at the end of this bridge.
他在那里
There he is. There he is! Yeah.
我看到你了，小子
I got you, Raines! I got you, boy!
再过来
That's it. Keep it comin'.
(港口船坞)
糟糕
Whoa! Shit! Shit.
One-Baker-eleven, be advised. Suspect heading westbound.
lBll注意，嫌犯向西行
朝东拦截
Head east to intercept.
保持路线 嫌犯正朝你的方向前进
One-Baker-eleven, maintain your course. Suspect heading in your direction.
他在码头底，正转向朝你前进
One-Baker-eleven, he's at the end of the pier turning towards you.
走开
Wait! Hang on! Hang onto it!
可恶
Oh, shit.
动啊
Move, move!
还好吗
Is he okay?
你没事吧，别乱动 我想是吧
- How are you doing? Are you all right? - Yeah.
- Are you okay? Just sit back. You all right? - I think so.
你确定?你刚穿过一面墙呢
Are you sure? 'Cause you just went through a wall.
长堤塔台，洛城警用直升机
Long Beach Tower, this is L.A.P.D. Air One in pursuit of suspect,
请求准许飞越机场
requesting permission to cross airfield.
不行，班机即将进场 请勿妄动
Negative, Air One. Incoming aircraft on approach.
Hold your position.
重覆，请勿退入机场领空
I repeat, do not enter airport air space.
Hey!
(距最后期限4分钟)
That one's got a broken leg!
他在那里
There he is. There he is.
Get outta the car, man!
下车
姓雷的
Raines!
曼斐呢?
- Where's, uh... Where's Memphis? - I don't know, man.
不知道
- He's not back yet. - What do you mean, he's not back yet?
他还没回来
什么叫还没回来?八点了
It's 8:00.
我是艾利
- Atley. - Time's up, Atley.
时间到，老艾 只有四十九辆，还差一辆
I've got 49 cars. That's one less than required.
把那小子带来，我们要解决他 什么小子?
- Bring the kid, and we'll settle this. - What kid is that?
你以为我指的是谁?
Oh, you know. The Cincinnati Kid, Billy the Kid. Which kid did you think I mean?
我想你指的是雷奇普
Oh, gee, I don't know. I think that maybe you mean Kip Raines.
我想你说的对
Well, gee. I think you're right.
情况很可笑
Yeah. Well, you know, it's a funny thing. That little son of a bitch evaded me.
那个小混球躲着我
找到他 要是找不到呢?
- Find him, Atley. - Well, what if I can't find him?
那就惩罚他哥哥，我不在乎
Then big brother takes the fall for the slipup. It doesn't matter much to me.
一个姓雷的就够用了
One Raines is as good as another. It never rains, but it pours.
不能雷声大雨点小吧
该死…
Son of a...! Just... Well, you know, I think you can thank your big brother.
感谢你哥吧
I think he just took your place under the guillotine.
他要代你上断头台了
Sorry, mate. We're all done here.
抱歉，兄弟，一切都结束了
- No, we're not done. This is number 50. - You're late.
不，还没有，这是第50辆
你退到了，滚吧
So sod off. You got a problem with that,
有疑问就去找卡先生谈
take it up with Calitri.
你迟到了
- You're late. - Wait. You're gonna argue with me over 12 minutes?
等等，你要跟我争这十二分钟
I just stole 50 cars for you in one night!
我一晚帮你偷了五十辆车
我有点累…有点急躁
All right? I'm a little tired. I'm a little wired!
我想我该值得称赞
And I think I deserve a little appreciation.
我说五十辆，不是四十九辆半
I said 50 cars, not 491/2.
四十九辆半?她没那么糟吧
491/2? She's not so bad, man. She's got, what? You know, some paint and, uh...
她只需要烤个漆
再加点玻璃纤维，没错
Some fiberglass. Yes, indeedy.
年签上写她价值六、七万
You know, and the book on her is 60, 70, call it 80.
是八万，用八万来算…
So you take 80, all right? You subtract it from 200. All right. And we make a deal.
从二十万中扣掉
交易达成
You take 80 from 200, and we call it even.
二十万扣八万我们就算互不相欠吧
Done.
同意
All right. Good. And this thing with my brother's over.
很好，我弟弟的事了结了
了结了
It's over.
了结、结束了
It's done. It's finished.
Done. Finished.
没人侮辱过我 或用枪指着我过
Nobody insults me. Nobody puts a gun to me head.
杀了他，把车毁了
Kill him. Shred the car.
好
All right. Where's Raymond Calitri's place?
姓卡的巢穴在哪?
Exeter Salvage and Steel. It's on the water. Why, are we goin'?
艾克西特废铁场
要去吗?凶杀组不准我们…
Because, you know, homicide specifically ordered us not to interfere.
去他的凶杀组
To hell with homicide.
独角兽
Unicorn.
什么?
- What? - Nothing.
没什么
你喜散射哪里?
So, where would you like it, sir?
射头还是胸口?
I n the head or in the chest?
胸口
- The chest. - My pleasure.
我的荣幸
Hey, wait a minute, fellas! Hold it.
等等，各位，计划改变
- Big change of plan here. - That's far enough, Atley.
别再靠近了，老艾
What are you doing? No, no, no!
你在干嘛?不
别过来
I said stop there, Atley!
老大派我上来问你一个问题
No, no. Calitri just sent me up here to ask you a question.
不会有事的
All right? Everything's gonna be all right. We got it covered.
带大家离开
Get my brother outta here.
Hey.
你挑孩子帮你做事是错的
You made a mistake pickin' a kid to do your dirty work.
更大的错误是挑上我弟弟
Made an even bigger mistake pickin' my kid brother.
而最大错特错的就是想杀我
And now, you just made the biggest mistake tryin' to kill me.
小心点
- No. Be careful with that. - This?
这个? 把它放下
- Just put it down. - That's right. You got a thing about wood.
对了，你对木头有癖好
把它放下
Just put it down.
不
No! No!
- No! - I... I...
我…
- No! - Oh, no.
糟糕
- Psst. - I'm good.
我还好
God! Jesus!
天啊
God.
你是谁? 我是警察
- Who are you? - I'm a police officer. You don't wanna do that now.
你不会想那么做的 我想
- Yeah, I do. - Listen to me.
听着，跟我走
You walk outta here with me, you got some options. You kill me... now you think about this...
你有很多选择
要是杀了我，你想想…
I'm a police officer. Your life will be over.
我是警察，你保证死定了
你弄错了，是你死定了
No, you've got that the wrong way around. If I kill you, your life's over.
结果也不会太坏 葬礼会有电视转播
Not all bad, though. Funeral will be on the telly. Everybody out there, pressed and dressed.
有仪仗队还有鸣枪21响致敬
Guard of honor. Twenty-one gun salute and the Stars and Stripes draped all over your coffin.
你的棺木上还会覆盖国旗
人生最光荣的一天
It'll be the greatest day of your life.
我面临最大的道德困境
Here I am smack dab in the middle of a moral dilemma, Randall.
你和你的伊琳诺 搞得城里鸡飞狗跳
You've torn this town to shreds with that little escapade of yours. You and your Eleanor.
但我知道你重出江湖的原因
But I understand what brought you back here.
手足之情…
A brother's love is a brother's love.
就是手足之情
你救了我一命
You saved my life, didn't you?
So what am I gonna do?
我该怎么办呢?
It's your call, Detective.
由你决定，警探
快走吧，曼斐 一切由我来处理
Get outta here, Randall. I'll clean this up.
走吧，趁我还没改变主意
Go, Randall, before I change my mind. Go.
Oh, uh, there's a container ship. At pier 14.
十四号码头有艘货柜船
你也许会想去查一下
You might want to check it out.
Oh. Look here. Can a good-lookin', hard-workin' chef get a beer around here?
英俊努力的大厨能喝啤酒吗?
小飞，你很闭，帮我拿啤酒
Come on, Tumbler. You ain't doin' nothin'. Hand me a beer, baby.
好耶，曼斐，大家快吃吧
All right, Memphis, guys, food! Thank you, sir.
谢了
Damn.
妈的
- Ow, ow. - Wait, wait, wait.
可怜的托比
Poor Toby, man. Sure looks like he's in a lot of pain.
他一定痛毙了
那样会痛，你杀了我算了
If that's pain, you can shoot me anytime.
性感小猫
Sexy, sexy.
他的受伤要是能启发你们…
If his unpleasant wounding...
has in some way enlightened the rest of you...
认清犯罪生活下的残酷结局
as to the grim finish below the glossy veneer of criminal life...
并让你们改变生活
and inspired you to change your ways,
那么他的伤… 就既尊贵又荣耀
then his injuries carry with it an inherent nobility and a supreme glory.
我们应该都很幸运
We should all be so fortunate.
你说"可怜的托比"
You say, "Poor Toby."
我说"可怜的我们"
I say, "Poor us."
他说话了
- He spoke. - Yeah.
我一直以为你是长堤人
Hey, man, I thought you were from Long Beach.
斐曼
Hey, Memphis. Hey.
我有东西要给你
I have something for you.
这是什么? 打开吧
- What is this? - Open it.
钥匙
Keys. Keys are good. What do I do with 'em?
钥匙很好，我要钥匙干嘛?
大家进来，快过来
Hey, everybody. Everybody.
Inside here. Let's go. Everybody, come on. Let's go.
大家快进来
Ladies and gentlemen, it's my great pleasure...
各位女士先生…
我很荣幸
来呈现…
to present...
天啊 你的伊琳诺
- Oh, man. Oh, man! - There you go. Eleanor.
- What? What? It's Eleanor. - How about that?
是伊琳诺呢
- Look at his face. - All yours.
她是你的了
她有点旧，给我几周
Now it's a heap, but give me a couple of weeks and it'll look like...
她就能脱胎换骨了
a streamlined butterfly.
你没有…
- You didn't... - Oh, no, no, no.
没有…我卖了摩托车买的
I, uh... I parted the chopper out for that.
I'm blown away.
我真惊讶
你卖了一辆车给我
You bought me a car.
是啊，她代表我对你的感谢
Well, yeah, you know. It's just a token of my appreciation for, uh...
你懂吧?
For everything.
That's the way it should be.
兄弟就该这样，没错
That's the way it should be. That's right.
- Yeah. - Why don't you get in there and go for a ride?
你何不开车兜一图
I know what you did.
我知道你所做的一切
谢谢你
- And I thank you. - I'll see you later, man.
待会见了
想兜风吗? 好啊
- You wanna go for a ride? - Hell, yes.
别这样
Oh, don't do this to me.
本片结束
泥古拉斯.凯奇----我的最爱! 字幕制作人:洪林 E-mail:guozi-@163.net QQ:20722945 本字幕版本按“简JIANYUE”电影版本调校 **版权仍为原制作人所有** 调校人：ZOZOSENSE